A Guide to the Amelia County (Va.) Fiduciary Records, 1736-1950
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Amelia County (Va.) Fiduciary Records 1736-1950
Library of Virginia
1145787, 1160434-1160442
8.35 cu.ft. (10 boxes)
Amelia County (Va.) Circuit Court.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These items came to the Library of Virginia in a transfer of court records from Amelia County as part of accessions 40724 and 41504.
Historical Information
Amelia County was named for Amelia Sophia Eleanora, daughter of King George II. It was formed from Prince George and Brunswick Counties by an act passed in 1734 to take effect on 25 March 1735. The county court first met on 9 May 1735.
Scope and Content
Amelia County (Va.) Fiduciary Records, 1736-1950, include miscellaneous records filed in a local court by trustees, administrators, executors, guardians, and committees that related to the performance of their duties managing a person's estate. These records typically include the following; bonds, appraisements, audits, inventories, accounts, estate divisions, settlements, dowery records, etc. Information related to enslaved people are commonly found in these records.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Additional Amelia County records can be found on microfilm at the Library of Virginia. Consult A Guide to Virginia County and City Records on Microfilm.
Contents List
- Administrators' Bonds, 1736-1845
  Administrators' Bonds, 1736-1779(broken series); 1780-1791, 1810-1830; 1833-1845
- Fiduciary Records, 1737-1897
  Administrators' Bonds, 1847-1849, 1851-1853; Agreements, 1808, 1815, 1838, 1842; Appraisements and Divisions, 1787; Committee Accounts, 1830; Committee Bonds, 1799-1897(broken series); Counter Security, 1767; Curator's Bonds, 1818-1851(broken series); Division of Estates, 1780-1835(broken series); Division of Slaves, 1813, 1855; Dower Assisgnment, 1798-1799, 1819; Estate Account, 1807; Estate of 1739-1881(broken series); Executors' Bonds, 1737-1782(broken series). Box also contains following accessioned item: Division of Estate of Edward Hudson, 1815 with Accessions 37990, 37993, 37995. Also Includes folder with various Fiduciary Records 1745, 1781, 1787, 1794 (4 documents). Documents from 1781 and 1794 belong to Accession 41507. For an additional Estate Account, 1744, see Oversized Box 8.
- Fiduciary Records, 1741-1897,undated
  Guardians' Bonds, 1838-1853(broken series); Homestead Papers, 1870, 1872, 1875; Inventories and Appraisements, 1757-1791(broken series); List of Certificates for Obtaining Probates and Administrations, undated, 1754-1755, 1846, 1849; Miscellaneous Fiduciary Records, undated, 1741-1897(broken series); Petition to Appoint Administrators, 1835; Receiver's Bond, 1834; Refunding Bonds, 1826-1858(broken series). For a list of guardians appointments, 1738-1753 with Accession 37995, see Oversized Box 11. Fiduciary Bonds can also be found in Oversized Book 1, Miscellaneous Bond Book, 1853.
- Guardians' Bonds, 1756-1805,undated
  Guardians' Bonds, undated, 1756-1770; 1776-1805,
- Accounts Current, 1778-1861
  Accounts Current, 1778-1861(broken series). Box also contains following item: Accounts Current of Estate of P. Anderson, 1826 with Accession 37990, 37993, 37995.
- Executors' Bonds, 1783-1853
  Executors' Bonds, 1783-1830; 1833-1853(broken series)
- Fiduciary Records, 1798-1895
  A Refunding Bonds, 1859, 1861; Sales of Estate of 1798, 1838; Sales Account of Estate of 1832; Sales and Accounts Current, 1843; Security, 1809-1872(broken series), Settlements of Estates, 1819, 1827, 1844-1858; 1854-1859; Trustee Accounts, 1826-1838; Trustee Appointment, 1895, Trustee Bond, 1847.
- Guardians' Bonds, 1806-1837
  Guardians' Bonds, 1806-1830; 1833-1837
- Guardians' Accounts, 1807-1861
  Guardians' Accounts, 1807-1810, 1820, 1830-1831, 1844-1855, 1861
- Estate Accounts, Fiduciary Accounts, Fiduciary Settlements, 1949-1950
  Estate Accounts, 1950; Fiduciary Accounts, 1949, Fiduciary Settlements, 1949-1950